# RUCHI **SHARMA**

Noida 201009 | 8470070005 | ruchi.sharma301196@gmail.com

## SUMMARY

Adaptable personality with extensive experience providing first-class results. Meets job demands and deadlines through diligent work-ethic and dedication to quality. Productive employee with proven track record of successful project management and producing quality outcomes through leadership and team motivation.

## **SKILLS**

- · C/C++ language
- · HTML, Javascript
- PHP
- · Strong work ethic.

- · Strong communication skills.
- · High Emotional Quotient.
- Knowledge of Geopolitical and World Affairs.

# **EXPERIENCE**

02/2022 - 03/2024

#### **Greeter and Proctor**

British Council - Noida, India

- · I was the Greeter & Proctor, Chief invigilator for IELTS Online Exam
- I have also been cross skilled for 6 months and have worked with various European countries and have worked in Operations for English courses
- · I greet and then proctor the whole examination session.
- · I have expertise in passports of various countries, especially China.
- I have interacted with people of almost 150+ countries like Italy, Portugal, Iran, Afghanistan, Germany, China, Indonesia, France and many more.
- I was cross-skilled in the English Department of British Council Europe. There I worked in Operations Management and worked on Salesforce and TCMS.
- Creating accounts of European students, linking accounts to particular courses and many other such tasks were done on a daily basis for thousands of students.
- I also catered the British Council Delhi branch and was in Operations for one month where I learnt how the process of admissions and other tasks took place.

12/2019 - 06/2020

#### Sales Associate

### Tata Homes (Conneqt Business Solutions) - Noida

- Greeted customers and provided exceptional customer service.
- · Assisted customers with information on various Tata Home Projects.
- · Handled Operations in maintaing customer data.
- Built relationships with customers to encourage repeat business.
- Upsold additional items based on customer interests and needs.

06/2019 - 11/2019

#### Customer Service Associate

Amazon - Noida, India

- I have worked for IN customers and handled both English/Hindi customers
- · I was part of Amazon Seller Team and used to handle cases with bulk orders
- Supported customer satisfaction, addressing escalated complaints with diplomacy and acknowledgment
- Provided friendly, attentive service by promptly responding to customer enquiries and processing order requests
- Handled complaints calmly and professionally, providing appropriate solutions to promote continued customer satisfaction.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

01/2019 B.Tech: Computer Science and Engineering

ABES Institute of Technology - Ghaziabad, UP

**01/2015 12th**: Science

Kendriya Vidhyalaya - Ghaziabad, UP

01/2013 10th: Science

Kendriya Vidhyalaya - Ghaziabad, UP

## **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- · Admin for College Fest.
- · Sports Admin for Zonal Competition.
- · Captain of College Girls Basketball Team.
- Margdarshak Programme( Mentorship and Industrial Exposition) in final year.
- Project on machine Learning(online exam through face recognition).

## HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- · Yoga, Gymnastics
- · Reading Novels and Newspaper.
- · Watching Podcasts, interviews related to Geopolitical and International affairs.
- · Travelling and exploring places, culture and people's lifestyle.